Here's my hot take on the Beastie Boys
song Fight for Your Right. When the band
first released this song back in 1986 on
its debut album Licensed to Ill,
admittedly there really wasn't anything
else out there quite like it. It was
brash. It was unapologetic. It was
aggressively juvenile. And for a lot of
people, it was the ultimate party rock
anthem. But, I would argue that it works
much better as a slow, quiet acoustic
song. This version by Andrew Paul
Woodworth that came out in 2007 does
what all great cover songs do. It
completely upends and reimagines the
original intent and meaning of the song.
>> [music]
>> In Woodworth's hands, the song is slow
and quiet. It's wistful. He really
conjures the loneliness and the sadness
of your teen years. And in a way it ends
up becoming this elegy to lost
childhood. But more than anything, he
finds that emotion, that thing that you
were missing when you first heard the
song. But for more cover songs that we
think are better than the originals,
listen to All Songs Considered wherever
you get podcasts. We did a whole episode
all about it and there's lots more to
discover.